Guide to the Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, and Transgender Task Force records, 1991-2009 UA.09.02.0001
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, and Transgender Task Force records
1991-2010
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Duke University. Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, and Transgender Task Force
UA.09.02.0001
3 Linear Feet
The LGBT Task Force makes ongoing assessments of attitudes and conditions throughout the University regarding gay, lesbian, bisexual, and transgender persons and issues. Records include minutes, agenda, correspondence, reports, printed email, clippings, printed matter, and other records of the Task Force.
Access Restrictions
For a period of twenty-five years from the origin of the material, permission in writing from the office of origin and the University Archivist is required for use of administrative records. After twenty-five years, records that have been processed may be consulted with the permission of the University Archivist.
Provenance
Transfer, 1999, 2003, 2006, 2014.
Historical Note
Established in 1991 by President H. Keith H. Brodie, the LGBT Task Force (Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, and Transgender) makes ongoing assessments of attitudes and conditions throughout the University regarding gay, lesbian, bisexual, and transgender persons and issues.
The LGBT Task Force also makes recommendations for changes and seeks implementation of these recommendations on issues such as (1) the University-wide environment for gay, lesbian, bisexual, and transgender students, staff, and faculty; (2) appropriate supportive services for such students, staff, and faculty; (3) educational programs for the entire University community; (4) other matters affecting the lives of gay, lesbian, bisexual, and transgender community members at Duke.
In the early 1990s, the LGBT Task Force advocated and organized for the creation of a LGBT Center dedicated to providing resources and training for students and staff at the University, which was staffed half time as the Center for LGBT Life in 1996, full time staff in 1999, and is now known as the Center for Sexual and Gender Diversity. The LGBT Task Force has also conducted surveys on sexuality among students to inform action and advocacy.
Collection Overview
Records include minutes, agenda, correspondence, reports, printed email, clippings, printed matter, and other records of the Task Force. Topics covered by the materials include University policies on same-sex marriages and benefits, surveys administered to students on sexuality and transgender issues, the creation and funding of the Center for LGBT Life (now the Center for Gender and Sexual Diversity), and many other subjects.
Conditions Governing Access
Records, such as search committee files or others pertaining to employment where individuals are identified, are closed for 70 years.
Conditions Governing Access
Electronic records in this collection have been migrated to a library server and digital use copies can only be accessed onsite in the Rubenstein Library Reading Room. To request access, please contact a reference archivist before coming to use these records.
Same-sex marriage -- United States; Gender identity -- United States; Gay community -- North Carolina; Lesbian community -- North Carolina; Duke University. Chapel; Duke University -- Students; Duke University -- Staff; Duke University -- Faculty
- "A Little Respect", 1993 (Box 1)
- Advertisement, Undated (Box 1)
- Agendas and Minutes: General Meeting Minutes, 1990-1992 (Box 1)
- Agendas and Minutes: Charge and Minutes, 1991-1992 (Box 1)
- Agendas and Minutes: Committee Minutes, 1991-1992 (Box 1)
- Agendas and Minutes: Scheduled Meetings, 1991-1992 (Box 1)
- Agenda and Minutes, 1991-1993 (Box 1)
- Agenda and Minutes, 1992-1994 (Box 1)
- Agenda and Minutes, 1993-1994 (Box 1)
- Agendas and Minutes: Task Force Minutes, 1994 (Box 1)
- Agendas and Minutes: First Meeting Info and Agenda, 1995 (Box 1)
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted until 2020
- Agendas and Minutes: Meeting Agendas / Packets, 1995 (Box 1)
- Agendas and Minutes: Meetings, 1995 (Box 1)
- Agenda and Minutes, 1995-1996 (Box 1)
  Restricted until 2021
- Agenda and Minutes, 1995-1997 (Box 1)
  Restricted until 2022
- Agenda and Minutes, 1996 (Box 1)
- Agenda and Minutes, 1996-1998 (Box 1)
  Restricted until 2023
- Alana Ennis, Duke Public Safety, 1995 (Box 1)
- Articles and Clippings: Articles and Support Material, 1991-1992 (Box 1)
- Articles and Clippings: Additional Materials, 1991-1992 (Box 1)
- Articles and Clippings: Magazine, Newspaper Clippings, and Articles, 1991-1993 (Box 1)
- Articles and Clippings: Additional Materials, 1992-1994 (Box 1)
- Articles and Clippings: Articles, 1993-1994 (Box 1)
- Articles and Clippings: Newspaper Clippings (Including 1997 East Campus Bridge Whitewash), 1995-1997 (Box 1)
- Articles and Clippings: Newspaper Clippings, 1996 (Box 1)
- Articles and Clippings: Newspaper Stories, 1996-1996 (Box 1)
- Ayanna Boyd-Williams, Director Graduate Student Affairs and Minority Programs, 1995 (Box 1)
- BiEALA Newsletter, 1995 (Box 1)
- Budget and Expenditures, 1993-1994 (Box 1)
- Chair of the Task Force, 1995 (Box 1)
- Chapel and Divinity School: Chapel Committee, 1995 (Box 1)
- Chapel and Divinity School: Divinity School and Duke Chapel, 1995 (Box 1)
- Chapel and Divinity School: Divinity School and Kathy Rudy, 1995-1997 (Box 1)
- Chapel and Divinity School: Duke Chapel, 1995 (Box 1)
- Chapel and Divinity School: Duke Chapel Policies Regarding Same Sex Unions, 1995 (Box 1)
- Committees: Nominating Committee, 1995 (Box 1)
- Committees: Re: University Committee on Nondiscrimination (Dale Martin's Committee), 1992 (Box 1)
- Committees: Subcommittee, 1991 (Box 1)
- Committees: Town Meeting: Orientation Committee, 1995 (Box 1)
- Committees: Transgender Issues Subcommittee, 2005-2008; 2 folders (Box 2)
  Restricted until 2033
- Committees: University Committee on Non-Discrimination, 1992 (Box 1)
- Correspondence Regarding Meetings and Events, 1991-1994 (Box 1)
- Correspondence, 1993-1994 (Box 1)
- Correspondence, 1995 November-1998 April (Box 1)
- Correspondence, 1997 (Box 1)
- Correspondence with Dean Campbell Duke Divinity School, 1996 (Box 1)
- Correspondence with Janet Dickerson, 1995 (Box 1)
- Correspondence with President Keohane, 1997 (Box 1)
- Correspondence: External Correspondence, 1991-1992 (Box 1)
- Development, 1993-1995 (Box 1)
- Dinners, 1995 (Box 1)
- Email, 1997 May- 1997 September (Box 1)
- Finances, 1995 (Box 1)
- Fundraising Brochures, 1993-1994 (Box 1)
- Ground Rules and Consensus, 1995 (Box 1)
- History: Task Force History, 1993 (Box 1)
- Information on Duke / LGB Groups, 1995 (Box 1)
- Kathy Rudy Situation, 1995 (Box 2)
  Restricted until 2065
- LGB Center: Rationale for Establishing a University Center for Lesbian, Gay, and Bisexual Life, 1993 (Box 1)
- LGB Center: University Center Proposal, 1993 (Box 1)
- LGB Center Committee, 1995 (Box 1)
- LGB Center and Staffing, 1996 (Box 1)
- LGB Center Location, 1996 (Box 1)
- LGB Center Director Interviews, 1996 (Box 2)
  Restricted until 2066
- LGB Center Staffing and Funding, 1996-1997 (Box 1)
- LGB Center Funding, 1997 (Box 1)
- Materials, 1993-1994 (Box 1)
- Materials, 1994-1995 (Box 1)
- Task Force Matters, 1994 (Box 2)
  Restricted until 2064
- Members, 1993-1994 (Box 1)
- Members, Rules, Etc., 1993-1994 (Box 1)
- Members, 1995 (Box 1)
- Members, 1995-1996 (Box 1)
- Members: Address Lists, 1995 (Box 1)
- Members: Offer Letters, 1995 (Box 1)
- Memorandum, 1993 (Box 1)
- Mission, 1995 (Box 1)
- Myrna Adams Meeting, 1995 (Box 1)
- Notes, 1992 (Box 1)
- Orientation, 1995 (Box 1)
- Orientation: Originals, 1995 (Box 1)
- Outreach to Greek Leaders, 1993 (Box 1)
- Parties and Events, 1995-1997 (Box 1)
- Policies: Recruitment Policy, 1988-1990 (Box 2)
- Policies: University Nondiscrimination, 1988-1992 (Box 2)
- Policies: Non-Discrimination Policy, 1988-1997 (Box 2)
- Policies: Duke Equal Opportunity Policy, 1991 (Box 1)
- Reports, 1992-1996 (Box 2)
- Reports: Annual Report, 1991-1992 (Box 2)
- Reports: Annual Report, 1991-1992 (Box 2)
- Reports: Annual Report, 1991-1996 (Box 2)
- Reports: Annual Report, 1994-1995 (Box 2)
- Reports: Annual Report, 1994-1996 (Box 2)
- Reports: Annual Report, 1995-1996 (Box 2)
- Reports: Annual Report, 1995-1996 (Box 2)
- Reports: Annual Report, 1996-1997; 2 folders (Box 2)
- Reports: Final Reports, 1991-1997 (Box 2)
- Reports: Non-Duke Reports, 1990-1992 (Box 2)
- Reports: Oregon Report, 1990 (Box 2)
- Reports: Task Force Progress Report, 1991 (Box 2)
- ROTC, 1998-1992 (Box 2)
- ROTC Policies, 1997 (Box 2)
- ROTC Policy, 1997 (Box 2)
- Same-Sex Spousal Benefits, 1994-1997 (Box 2)
- Same-Sex Spousal Benefits at Other Universities, 1997 (Box 2)
- Same-Sex Spousal Benefits Reports, 1990-1991 (Box 2)
- Same-Sex Spousal Benefits to Graduate and Professional Students, 1995 (Box 2)
- Schedules, 1995 (Box 2)
- Strategic Plan, 1998-1999 (Box 2)
  Restricted until 2024
- Survey on Sexuality, 1991-1992; 2 folders (Box 2)
- Survey on Sexuality Findings, 1992 (Box 2)
- Surveys, 1997 (Box 2)
- Task Force Town Meeting, 1995-1996 (Box 2)
- Vice Chair of the Task Force, 1995 (Box 2)
- William's Party, 1995 (Box 2)
- Miscellaneous, 1990-1992 (Box 2)
- Miscellaneous, 1992-1993 (Box 2)
- Miscellaneous, 1994-1997 (Box 2)
- Miscellaneous, 1995-1996 (Box 2)
- Miscellaneous, 1995-1997 (Box 2)
- Miscellaneous, 1998 (Box 2)
- General, 1991-1999 (Digital-materials UA09020001-SET-0001, Box Digital Media Box 1)
  Scope and Contents
  6 files, 310 KB, documents
  Restricted until 2024.
- General, 1998-2000 (Box 2)
  Restricted until 2025
- General, 1999-2000 (Digital-materials UA09020001-SET-0001, Box Digital Media Box 1)
  12 files, 198 KB, documents
  Restricted until 2025.
- General, 2000-2001; 2 folders (Box 2)
  Restricted until 2026
- General, 2000-2001 (Digital-materials UA09020001-SET-0001, Box Digital Media Box 1)
  25 files, 207 KB, documents
  Restricted until 2026.
- General, 2001-2002; 2 folders (Box 2)
  Restricted until 2027
- General, 2001-2002 (Digital-materials UA09020001-SET-0001, Box Digital Media Box 1)
  48 files, 874 KB, documents
  Restricted until 2027.
- General, 2003-2004 (Box 2)
  Restricted until 2029
- General, 2003-2004 (Digital-materials UA09020001-SET-0001, Box Digital Media Box 1)
  19 files, 112 KB, documents
  Restricted until 2029.
- General, 2004-2005 (Digital-materials UA09020001-SET-0001, Box Digital Media Box 1)
  20 files, 122 KB, documents and PDFs
  Restricted until 2030.
- General, 2005-2006 (Digital-materials UA09020001-SET-0001, Box Digital Media Box 1)
  22 files, 913 KB, documents and PDFs
  Restricted until 2031.
- General, 2006-2007 (Digital-materials UA09020001-SET-0001, Box Digital Media Box 1)
  22 files, 406 KB, documents and PDFs
  Restricted until 2032.
- General, 2007-2008 (Box 2)
- General, 2007-2008 (Digital-materials UA09020001-SET-0001, Box Digital Media Box 1)
  10 files, 127 KB, documents and PDFs
  Restricted until 2033.
- General, 2008-2009 (Box 2)
  Restricted until 2034
- General, 2008-2009 (Digital-materials UA09020001-SET-0001, Box Digital Media Box 1)
  27 files, 301 KB, documents
  Restricted until 2034.
- General, 2009-2010 (Digital-materials UA09020001-SET-0001, Box Digital Media Box 1)
  5 files, 108 KB, documents and PDFs
  Restricted until 2035.
- General, undated (Digital-materials UA09020001-SET-0001, Box Digital Media Box 1)
  4 files, 76 KB, documents and PDFs